<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on rishab_m</title>
    <link>https://lazycodes7.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on rishab_m</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 May 2022 14:56:36 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lazycodes7.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Week-1 (Community Bonding) 20th May - 27th May</title>
      <link>https://lazycodes7.github.io/posts/week1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2022 14:56:36 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lazycodes7.github.io/posts/week1/</guid>
      <description>Introduction    Hi new readers! I am Rishab Mudliar and I am currently in the final year of my Computer Science Major. This blog is part of a series dedicated to noting down my activities during the period of Google Summer of Code.
GSoC    Google Summer of Code or the acronym GSoC is a program aimed at people in tech looking to contribute to open-source software development.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bertelsmann Scholarship</title>
      <link>https://lazycodes7.github.io/posts/bertelsmann-scholarship/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 15:27:56 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lazycodes7.github.io/posts/bertelsmann-scholarship/</guid>
      <description>Today I wanted to talk about my experience about the &amp;ldquo;Bertelsmann Scholarship&amp;rdquo; via this post. I hope after reading this, more people will be interested in what I believe is a truly amazing program for learning something that might interest you!
Beginnings    It all started when one of my friends recommending this to program back in November. The application had 3 choices &amp;ldquo;AI&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;Data&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;Cloud&amp;rdquo;. I decided to go with AI as I always wanted to try it out but didn&amp;rsquo;t have much knowledge about it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Networking Protocols</title>
      <link>https://lazycodes7.github.io/posts/networking-protocols/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Mar 2020 14:56:36 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lazycodes7.github.io/posts/networking-protocols/</guid>
      <description>Protocols.    So what exactly are protocols? Protocols according to me are certain set of rules that we use to communicate with each other
Why do we use Protocols ?    So in brief I explained about protocols but the next question is why do we need them.Let&amp;rsquo;s consider an example,say I am Thor and I wanna talk to some new avenger(Night Monkey) then first I need Night Monkey&amp;rsquo;s permission to talk(although I can just smash him with thunder and make him talk) and then Night Monkey will talk to Thor and so on a talk session starts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My first post!</title>
      <link>https://lazycodes7.github.io/posts/first/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 14:27:35 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lazycodes7.github.io/posts/first/</guid>
      <description>My First Blog!    Hi there! I am Rishab Mudliar and coincidentally i am writing my first blog post on the first day of this year (I know this is a bad joke). I don&amp;rsquo;t know how bad this will be but i hope it&amp;rsquo;s not that bad that nobody understands..
Why Ubuntu?    1. Ubuntu is user-friendly    Many computer users consider Linux-based systems hard to use and made for developers.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
